<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE locale SYSTEM "../../lib/pkp/dtd/locale.dtd">
<!--
  * locale/pt_BR/admin.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2014-2016 Simon Fraser University Library
  * Copyright (c) 2003-2016 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Localization strings for the pt_BR (Português (Brasil)) locale (Site administration).
  -->
<locale name="pt_BR" full_name="Português (Brasil)">
	<message key="admin.hostedPresses">Hosted Presses</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.pressRedirect">Press redirect</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.pressRedirectInstructions">Requests to the main site will be redirected to this press. This may be useful if the site is hosting only a single press, for example.</message>
	<message key="admin.settings.noPressRedirect">Do not redirect</message>

	<message key="admin.languages.primaryLocaleInstructions">This will be the default language for the site and any hosted presses.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.supportedLocalesInstructions">Select all locales to support on the site. The selected locales will be available for use by all presses hosted on the site, and also appear in a language select menu to appear on each site page (which can be overridden on press-specific pages). If multiple locales are not selected, the language toggle menu will not appear and extended language settings will not be available to presses.</message>
	<message key="admin.locale.maybeIncomplete">* Marked locales may be incomplete.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.confirmUninstall">Are you sure you want to uninstall this locale? This may affect any hosted presses currently using the locale.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.installNewLocalesInstructions">Select any additional locales to install support for in this system. Locales must be installed before they can be used by hosted presses. See the OMP documentation for information on adding support for new languages.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.noLocalesToDownload">No locales are available for download.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.downloadFailed">The locale download failed. The error message(s) below describe the failure.</message>
	<message key="admin.languages.downloadUnavailable"><![CDATA[<p>Downloading language packs from the Public Knowledge Project web server is not currently available because:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>Your server does not have or allow execution of the GNU "tar" utility</li>
		<li>OMP is unable to modify the locale registry file, typically "registry/locales.xml".</li>
	</ul>
<p>Language packs can be manually downloaded from the <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca" target="_blank">PKP web site</a>.</p>]]></message>

	<message key="admin.languages.confirmDisable">Are you sure you want to disable this locale? This may affect any hosted presses currently using the locale.</message>

	<message key="admin.systemVersion">OMP Version</message>
	<message key="admin.systemConfiguration">OMP Configuration</message>
	<message key="admin.systemConfigurationDescription"><![CDATA[OMP configuration settings from <tt>config.inc.php</tt>.]]></message>
	<message key="admin.presses.pressSettings">Press Settings</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.noneCreated">No presses have been created.</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.createInstructions">You will automatically be enrolled as the manager of this press. After creating a new press, you will be redirected to its settings wizard, to complete the initial press setup.</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.urlWillBe">The press URL will be {$sampleUrl}</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.enablePressInstructions">Enable this press to appear publicly on the site</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.pressDescription">Press description</message>
	<message key="admin.presses.addPress">Add Press</message>

	<message key="admin.settings.oaiRegistrationDescription"><![CDATA[To have the contents of all presses hosted on this site indexed within a globally distributed system of research databases, <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/harvester/add.php" target="_blank">register</a> your site's URL with the Public Knowledge Project metadata <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/harvester/" target="_blank">harvester</a>. This tool collects the metadata from each indexed item in this press, enabling accurate and collective searching among the research sites that adhere to the <a href="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/openarchivesprotocol.htm#Introduction" target="_blank">Open Archives Initiative Protocol for Metadata Harvesting</a>.
<br /><br />
<a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/harvester/add.php" target="_blank">Click here</a> and enter <span class="highlight">{$siteUrl}</span> under <strong>Site URL</strong>, and <span class="highlight">{$oaiUrl}</span> under <strong>Base URL for OAI Archive</strong>.
<br /><br />
Note that the OAI interface can be disabled for this site by editing the OMP system configuration. Future versions of OMP will allow the OAI interface to be enabled or disabled for individual presses within the site.]]></message>

	<!-- System Information -->
	<message key="admin.overwriteConfigFileInstructions"><![CDATA[<h4>NOTE!</div>
<p>The system could not automatically overwrite the configuration file. To apply your configuration changes you must open <tt>config.inc.php</tt> in a suitable text editor and replace its contents with the contents of the text field below.</p>]]></message>

	<message key="admin.contexts.confirmDelete">Tem certeza que deseja apagar definitivamente esta editora e todo seu conteúdo?</message>
	<message key="admin.contexts.create">Criar Editora</message>
	<message key="admin.contexts.form.titleRequired">Um título é necessário.</message>
	<message key="admin.contexts.form.pathRequired">Um caminho é requerido.</message>
	<message key="admin.contexts.form.pathAlphaNumeric">O caminho pode conter somente caracteres alfanuméricos, sublinhado, e hífens, e deve começar e terminar com um caractere alfanumérico.</message>
	<message key="admin.contexts.form.pathExists">O caminho selecionado já é utilizado por outra editora.</message>
</locale>
