<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE locale SYSTEM "../../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/locale.dtd">

<!--
  * plugins/generic/usageStats/locale/en_US/locale.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2014-2015 Simon Fraser University Library
  * Copyright (c) 2003-2015 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Localization strings
  -->

<locale name="en_US" full_name="U.S. English">
	<message key="plugins.reports.usageStats.report.displayName">OMP usage statistics report</message>
	<message key="plugins.reports.usageStats.report.description">OMP default usage statistics report (COUNTER ready)</message>

	<message key="plugins.generic.usageStats.optout.description"><![CDATA[
		<h3>General Privacy Information</h3>
		<p>Please refer to our general <a href="{$privacyStatementUrl}">privacy statement</a>.</p>
		<h3>Usage Statistics</h3>
		<p>In order to be able to analyse usage and impact of our publications, we collect and log access to the homepage, categories, series, books and files. In the process all data is anonymised. No personal information is logged. IP addresses are anonymised by being hashed (using <em>SHA 256</em>) in combination with a <em>secure 64 characters long salt</em> that is automatically <em>randomly generated and overridden on a daily basis</em>. Therefore IP addresses cannot be reconstructed.</p>
		<p>The following information is collected next to the anonymised IP addresses:</p>
		<ul>
		<li>Access type (i.e. administrative)</li>
		<li>Request time</li>
		<li>Requested URL</li>
		<li>HTTP status code</li>
		<li>Browser</li>
		</ul>
		<p>The collected data is only used for evaluation purposes. No IP addresses are mapped to user IDs. It is technically impossible to trace a specific set of data to a specific IP address.</p>]]></message> 
	<message key="plugins.generic.usageStats.optout.done"><![CDATA[
		<p>You successfully opted out of usage statistics collection. While you see this message no statictics will be collected from your usage of this site. Click the below button to revert your decision.</p>]]></message>
	<message key="plugins.generic.usageStats.optin">Opt In</message>
	<message key="plugins.generic.usageStats.optout">Opt Out</message>
	<message key="plugins.generic.usageStats.optout.cookie"><![CDATA[
		<p>If you wish you can opt-out of the data collection process. By clicking the opt-out button below, you can actively decide against participating in the statistical analysis. When clicking the opt-out button a <em>cookie</em> is being created on your system to store your decision. If the privacy settings of your browser lead to cookies being automatically deleted you will have to opt-out again the next time you access this website. The cookie is only valid for one browser. If you use a different browser, you will have to opt out again. No individual information is stored within this cookie. This cookie lease is valid for one year after your last access.</p>
		<p>Please bear in mind that general server logs are not affected by your decision to opt-out of the detailed evaluation process. Please refer to our general <a href="{$privacyStatementUrl}">privacy statement</a>.</p>]]></message>

	<message key="plugins.reports.usageStats.metricType">OMP/COUNTER</message>
	<message key="plugins.reports.usageStats.metricType.full">Open Monograph Press statistics (COUNTER ready)</message>
</locale>
