<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000000.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2003-2008 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Introduction to OMP Main 
  *
  * $Id$
  -->

<topic id="intro/topic/000000" locale="en_US" title="Introduction to OMP" toc="index/toc/000000" subtoc="intro/toc/000000" key="intro.index">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>This press uses the Open Monograph Press software for management and publishing support. OMP is an open source solution to managing and publishing scholarly presses online. OMP is a highly flexible editor-operated press management and publishing system that can be downloaded for free and installed on a local Web server. It has been designed to reduce the time and energy devoted to the clerical and managerial tasks associated with editing a press, while improving the record-keeping and efficiency of editorial processes. It seeks to improve the scholarly and public quality of press publishing through a number of innovations, from making press policies more transparent to improving indexing.</p>]]>	
	</section>
	<section title="System Background">
		<![CDATA[<p><em>OMP is a press and web site management and publishing system</em>. OMP covers all aspects of online press publishing, from establishing a press website to operational tasks such as the author's submission process, peer review, editing, publication, archiving, and indexing of the press. OMP also helps to manage the people aspects of organizing a press, including keeping track of the work of editors, reviewers, and authors, notifying readers, and assisting with the correspondence.</p><p><em>OMP is flexible and scalable</em>. A single installation of OMP can support the operation of many presses. Each press has its own unique URL as well as its own look and feel. OMP can enable a single editor to manage all aspects of a press and the press's website, or OMP will support an international team of editors with diverse responsibilities for a press's multiple acquisitionsArrangements.</p><p><em>OMP supports the principle of extending access</em>. This system is intended not only to assist with press publishing, but to demonstrate how costs of press publishing can be reduced to the point where providing readers with "open access" to the contents of the press may be a viable option. The case for open access is spelled out over a wide series of monographs stemming from this project which are freely available under Publications at the University of British Columbia <a href="http://pkp.ubc.ca/" target="_blank">Public Knowledge Project</a> website.</p><p><em>The origins of OMP</em>. The system was first released in 2002 as a research and development initiative of the Public Knowledge Project at the University of British Columbia, with the support of the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada, Max Bell Foundation, the Pacific Press Endowment, and the MacArthur Foundation. Its continuing development is currently overseen by a partnership among UBC's Public Knowledge Project, the Canadian Center for Studies in Publishing and the Simon Fraser University Library. For more information, see the <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/" target="_blank">Public Knowledge Project @ Simon Fraser University</a> website.</p>]]>	
	</section>
	<section title="Management Structure">
		<![CDATA[<h5>Editorial Process</h5><p>OMP moves submissions to the press through five steps in the editorial process, which will be managed by one or more of the editors.</p><ol><li><em>Unassigned Queue:</em> Items begin here and are assigned to one or more editors.</li><li><em>Submission Review:</em> Items undergo peer review and editorial decision.</li><li><em>Submission Editing:</em> Items undergo copyediting, layout, and proofreading. </li><li><em>Table of Contents:</em> Items are ordered for publication and are published.</li></ol><h5>Editorial Roles</h5>(Assigned in Press Management)<ul><li><em>Press Manager:</em> Sets up the press and staffs editorial roles (can also serve as an Editor and other roles).</li><li><em>Editor:</em> Oversees editorial process; can assign submissions to Acquisitions Editors to see through Submission Review and Submission Editing; undertakes scheduling of content and publishing of press.</li><li><em>Acquisitions Editor:</em> Oversees Submission Review and possibly Submission Editing for assigned submissions.</li><li><em>Copyeditor:</em> Works with submissions to improve grammar and clarity, poses questions to author on possible errors, and ensures strict adherence to press's bibliographic and textual style.</li><li><em>Layout Editor:</em> Transforms copyedited submissions into galleys in HTML, PDF, and/or PS files in the proper format for electronic publishing.</li><li><em>Proofreader:</em> Reads galleys for typographic and formatting errors.</li></ul>
<p align="center"><a href="{$baseUrl}/locale/{$locale}/edprocesslarge.png"><img src="{$baseUrl}/locale/{$locale}/edprocess.png" width="480" height="542" border="0" alt="" /></a></p>]]>
	</section>
	<section title="Support">
		<![CDATA[<p>A support forum and bug reporting system for technical issues can be accessed via the PKP <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/support/forum/" target="_blank">web site</a>.</p><p>Users who have questions about interacting with a particular monograph project's site using OMP or that monograph project's policies are encouraged to contact the monograph project's principal or support contacts, listed on the monograph project web site's About page.</p>]]>
	</section>
</topic>
