<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE locale SYSTEM "../../lib/pkp/dtd/locale.dtd">

<!--
  * defaultSettings.xml
  *
  * Copyright (c) 2003-2010 John Willinsky
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * Localization strings for the en_US (U.S. English) locale (default press settings).
  -->

<locale name="en_US" full_name="U.S. English">
	<!--
	 *
	 * DEFAULT - Default settings for setup items.
	 *
	-->
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.artwork">Artwork</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.appendix">Appendix</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.appendix.designation">99A</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.bibliography">Bibliography</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.bibliography.designation">99B</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.manuscript">Manuscript</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.manuscript.designation">99Z</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.chapter">Chapter</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.glossary">Glossary</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.glossary.designation">99G</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.index">Index</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.index.designation">99I</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.preface">Preface</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.preface.designation">00P</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.prospectus">Prospectus</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.prospectus.designation">88P</message>
	<message key="default.monographFileTypes.tablesAndFigures">Tables and Figures</message>

	<message key="default.publicationFormats.hardcover">Hardcover</message>
	<message key="default.publicationFormats.hardcover.designation">HC</message>
	<message key="default.publicationFormats.softcover">Softcover</message>
	<message key="default.publicationFormats.softcover.designation">SC</message>
	<message key="default.publicationFormats.ebook">EBook</message>
	<message key="default.publicationFormats.ebook.designation">EBook</message>

	<message key="default.groups.name.siteAdmin">Site Admin</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.siteAdmin">Site Admins</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.pressManager">Press manager</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.pressManager">Press managers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.pressManager">PM</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.editor">Press editor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.editor">Press editors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.editor">PE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.productionEditor">Production editor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.productionEditor">Production editors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.productionEditor">PE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.seriesEditor">Series editor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.seriesEditor">Series editors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.seriesEditor">AcqE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.copyeditor">Copyeditor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.copyeditor">Copyeditors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.copyeditor">CE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.proofreader">Proofreader</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.proofreader">Proofreaders</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.proofreader">PR</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.designer">Designer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.designer">Designers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.designer">Design</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.reviewer">Reviewer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.reviewer">Reviewers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.reviewer">Reviewer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.internalReviewer">Internal Reviewer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.internalReviewer">Internal Reviewers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.internalReviewer">IR</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.externalReviewer">External Reviewer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.externalReviewer">External Reviewers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.externalReviewer">ER</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.marketing">Marketing and sales coordinator</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.marketing">Marketing and sales coordinators</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.marketing">MS</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.funding">Funding coordinator</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.funding">Funding coordinators</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.funding">FC</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.indexer">Indexer</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.indexer">Indexers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.indexer">IND</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.layoutEditor">Layout Editor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.layoutEditor">Layout Editors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.layoutEditor">LE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.author">Author</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.author">Authors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.author">Author</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.chapterAuthor">Chapter Author</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.chapterAuthor">Chapter Authors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.chapterAuthor">CA</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.volumeEditor">Volume editor</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.volumeEditor">Volume editors</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.volumeEditor">VE</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.translator">Translator</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.translator">Translators</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.translator">Trans</message>
	<message key="default.groups.name.reader">Reader</message>
	<message key="default.groups.plural.reader">Readers</message>
	<message key="default.groups.abbrev.reader">READ</message>

	<message key="default.pressSettings.checklist.notPreviouslyPublished">The submission has not been previously published, nor is it before another press for consideration (or an explanation has been provided in Comments to the Editor).</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.checklist.fileFormat">The submission file is in the Microsoft Word, RTF, OpenDocument, or WordPerfect file format.</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.checklist.addressesLinked">Where available, URLs for the references have been provided.</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.checklist.submissionAppearance">The text is single-spaced; uses a 12-point font; employs italics, rather than underlining (except with URL addresses); and all illustrations, figures, and tables are placed within the text at the appropriate points, rather than at the end.</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.checklist.bibliographicRequirements"><![CDATA[The text adheres to the stylistic and bibliographic requirements outlined in the <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/about/submissions#authorGuidelines" target="_new">Author Guidelines</a>, which is found in About the Press.]]></message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.privacyStatement">The names and email addresses entered in this press site will be used exclusively for the stated purposes of this press and will not be made available for any other purpose or to any other party.</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.openAccessPolicy">This press provides immediate open access to its content on the principle that making research freely available to the public supports a greater global exchange of knowledge.</message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.copyeditInstructions"><![CDATA[The copyediting stage is intended to improve the flow, clarity, grammar, wording, and formatting of the monograph. It represents the last chance for the author to make any substantial changes to the text, as the next stage is restricted to typos and formatting corrections.

The file to be copyedited is in Word or .rtf format and therefore can be easily edited as a word processing document. This set of  instructions displayed here proposes two approaches to copyediting. The one is based on Microsoft Word's Track Changes feature and requires that the copyeditor, editor and author have access to this program. A second system, that is software independent, has been borrowed, with permission, from the Harvard Educational Review. The press editor is in a position to modify these instructions, so suggestions can be made to improve the process for this press.

<h4>Copyediting Systems</h4>

<strong>1. Microsoft Word's Track Changes</strong>

Under Tools in the menu bar, the feature Track Changes enables the copyeditor to make insertions (text appears in color) and deletions (text appears crossed out in color or in the margins as deleted). The copyeditor can post queries to both the author (Author Queries) and to the editor (Editor Queries) by inserting these queries in square brackets. The copyedited version is then uploaded and the editor is notified. The editor then reviews the text and notifies the author.

The editor and author should leave those changes with which they are satisfied. If further changes are necessary, the editor and author can make changes to the initial insertions or deletions, as well as make new insertions or deletions elsewhere in the text. Authors and editors should respond to each of the queries addressed to them, with responses placed inside the square brackets.

After the text has been reviewed by editor and author, the copyeditor will make a final pass over the text accepting the changes in preparation for the layout and galley stage.


<strong>2. Harvard Educational Review </strong>

<strong>Instructions for Making Electronic Revisions to the Manuscript</strong>

Please follow the following protocol for making electronic revisions to your manuscript:

<strong>Responding to suggested changes</strong>
&nbsp; For each of the suggested changes that you accept, unbold the text
&nbsp; For each of the suggested changes that you do not accept, re-enter the original text and <strong>bold</strong> it

<strong>Making additions and deletions</strong>
&nbsp; Indicate additions by <strong>bolding</strong> the new text
&nbsp; Replace deleted sections with: <strong>[deleted text]</strong>
&nbsp; If you delete a sentence or more, please indicate with a note, e.g., <strong>[deleted 2 sentences]</strong>

<strong>Responding to Queries to the Author (QAs)</strong>
&nbsp; Keep all QAs intact and bolded within the text. Do not delete them
&nbsp; To reply to a QA, add a comment after it. Comments should be delimited using:
<strong>[Comment:</strong>]
&nbsp; e.g., <strong>[Comment: Expanded discussion of methodology as you suggested]</strong>

<strong>Making comments</strong>
&nbsp; Use comments to explain organizational changes or major revisions
&nbsp; e.g., <strong>[Comment: Moved the above paragraph from p. 5 to p. 7]</strong>
&nbsp; Note: When referring to page numbers, please use the page numbers from the printed copy of the manuscript that was sent to you. This is important since page numbers may change as a document is revised electronically.

<h4>An Illustration of an Electronic Revision</h4>

<strong>The original "manuscript" file</strong>

Before making dramatic departures from the structure and organization of your original manuscript, please check in with the co-chairs of your piece. After you are finished with your revisions, rename the file from AuthorNameQA.doc to AuthorNameQAR.doc (e.g., from LeeQA.doc to LeeQAR.doc). Print out a hardcopy of your manuscript and mail it with a floppy disk containing the completely revised and renamed word processing file.


<strong>Manuscript returned to the author with queries and suggestions</strong>

Before making dramatic departures from the structure and organization of <strong>the manuscript that we are returning to you</strong>, please check in with the <strong>editors who are co-chairing</strong> your piece. After you are finished with your revisions, rename the file from AuthorNameQA.doc to AuthorNameQAR.doc (e.g., from LeeQA.doc to LeeQAR.doc). Print out a hardcopy of your manuscript and mail it with a floppy disk containing the completely revised and renamed word processing file. <strong>[QA: In this paragraph, it might help to stress the importance of following carefully the instructions for making electronic revisions. Otherwise the editing process may be slowed considerably]</strong>

<strong>Revised manuscript sent back to HER</strong>

Before making dramatic departures from the structure and organization of the manuscript that we are returning to you, please check in with the editors who are co-chairing your piece. <strong>Please understand that failure to follow the following instructions may significantly delay the publication of your manuscript.</strong>

After you are finished with your revisions, rename the file from AuthorNameQA.doc to AuthorNameQAR.doc (e.g., from LeeQA.doc to LeeQAR.doc). Print out a hardcopy of your manuscript and mail it with a floppy disk containing the <strong>[deleted word]</strong> revised and renamed word processing file. <strong>[QA: In this paragraph, it might help to stress the importance of following carefully the instructions for making electronic revisions. Otherwise the editing process may be slowed considerably] [Comment: I added a sentence in response to your suggestion.]</strong>

<strong>Notes:</strong>
&bull; Unbolded text indicates acceptance of the suggested changes to the first sentence
&bull; Sentence added in response to QA. Bold text indicates addition of new text
&bull; [deleted word] indicates deletion of "completely"
&bull; Comment contains a reply to the editors' QA]]></message>

	<message key="default.pressSettings.refLinkInstructions"><![CDATA[<h4>To Add Reference Linking to the Layout Process</h4>
	<p>When turning a submission into HTML or PDF, make sure that all hyperlinks in the submission are active.</p>
	<h4>A. When the Author Provides a Link with the Reference</h4>
	<ol>
	<li>While the submission is still in its word processing format (e.g., Word), add the phrase VIEW ITEM to the end of the reference that has a URL.</li>
	<li>Turn that phrase into a hyperlink by highlighting it, and using Word's Insert Hyperlink tool and the URL prepared in #2.</li>
	</ol>
	<h4>B. Enabling Readers to Search Google Scholar For References</h4>
	<ol>
	<li>While the submission is still in its word processing format (e.g., Word), copy the title of the work referenced in the References list (if it appears to be too common a title – e.g., "Peace" – then copy author and title).</li>
	<li>Paste the reference's title between the %22's, placing a + between each word: http://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=%22PASTE+TITLE+HERE%22&hl=en&lr=&btnG=Search</li>
	<li>Add the phrase GS SEARCH to the end of each citation in the submission's References list.</li>
	<li>Turn that phrase into a hyperlink by highlighting it, and using Word's Insert Hyperlink tool and the URL prepared in #2.</li>
	</ol>
	<h4>C. Enabling Readers to Search for References with a DOI</h4>
	<ol>
	<li>While the submission is still in Word, copy a batch of references into CrossRef Text Query http://www.crossref.org/freeTextQuery/</li>
	<li>Paste each DOI that the Query provides in the following URL (between = and &): http://www.cmaj.ca/cgi/external_ref?access_num=PASTE DOI#HERE&link_type=DOI</li>
	<li>Add the phrase CrossRef to the end of each citation in the submission's References list.</li>
	<li>Turn that phrase into a hyperlink by highlighting the phrase and using Word's Insert Hyperlink tool and the appropriate URL prepared in #2.</li>
	</ol>]]></message>

	<message key="default.pressSettings.proofingInstructions"><![CDATA[<p>The proofreading stage is intended to catch any errors in the galley's spelling, grammar, and formatting. More substantial changes cannot be made at this stage, unless discussed with the Section Editor. In Layout, click on VIEW PROOF to see the HTML, PDF and other available file formats used in publishing this item.</p>
<h4>For Spelling and Grammar Errors</h4>

<p>Copy the problem word or groups of words and paste them into the Proofreading Corrections box with "CHANGE-TO" instructions to the editor as follows...</p>

<pre>1. CHANGE...
then the others
TO...
than the others</pre>
<br />
<pre>2. CHANGE...
Malinowsky
TO...
Malinowski</pre>
<br />

<h4>For Formatting Errors</h4>

<p>Describe the location and nature of the problem in the Proofreading Corrections box after typing in the title "FORMATTING" as follows...</p>
<br />
<pre>3. FORMATTING
The numbers in Table 3 are not aligned in the third column.</pre>
<br />
<pre>4. FORMATTING
The paragraph that begins "This last topic..." is not indented.</pre>]]></message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.emailSignature"><![CDATA[________________________________________________________________________
{$pressName}
{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}
]]></message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.forReaders"><![CDATA[We encourage readers to sign up for the publishing notification service for this press. Use the <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/user/register">Register</a> link at the top of the homepage for the press. This registration will result in the reader receiving the Table of Contents by email for each new monograph of the press. This list also allows the press to claim a certain level of support or readership. See the press's <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/about/submissions#privacyStatement">Privacy Statement</a> which assures readers that their name and email address will not be used for other purposes.]]></message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.forAuthors"><![CDATA[Interested in submitting to this press? We recommend that you review the <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/about">About the Press</a> page for the press's section policies, as well as the <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/about/submissions#authorGuidelines">Author Guidelines</a>. Authors need to <a href="{$indexUrl}/{$pressPath}/user/register">register</a> with the press prior to submitting, or if already registered can simply <a href="{$indexUrl}/index/login">log in</a> and begin the 5 step process.]]></message>
	<message key="default.pressSettings.forLibrarians"><![CDATA[We encourage research librarians to list this press among their library's electronic press holdings. As well, it may be worth noting that this press's open source publishing system is suitable for libraries to host for their faculty members to use with presses they are involved in editing (see <a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/omp">Open Monograph Press</a>).]]></message>
</locale>
